<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>All Posts - Matt Adorjan</title><link>http://example.org/posts/</link><description>All Posts | Matt Adorjan</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/posts/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Using Kyverno Policies for Kubernetes Governance</title><link>http://example.org/posts/2021-12-31-kyverno-kubernetes-policies-governance/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>http://example.org/posts/2021-12-31-kyverno-kubernetes-policies-governance/</guid><description><![CDATA[<h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2>
<p>Kyverno is a great tool that can be installed into any Kubernetes cluster, allowing cluster administrators to enforce policies for resources in the cluster, and even modify resources before they are applied. Kyverno can be used to ensure deployments are secure, ensure deployments meet certain organizational criteria (e.g. define a cost center label), or even ensure all deployments mount a common volume.</p>
<p><a href="https://dev.to/mda590/using-kyverno-policies-for-kubernetes-governance-3e17" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Click here to read more!</a></p>]]></description></item><item><title>Trying out AWS Controllers for Kubernetes (ACK)</title><link>http://example.org/posts/2021-08-24-trying-out-ack-controllers/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2021 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>http://example.org/posts/2021-08-24-trying-out-ack-controllers/</guid><description><![CDATA[<h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2>
<p>AWS Controllers for Kubernetes (ACK) allows creating AWS resources via the same process you use to deploy other resources in Kubernetes. ACK uses the Kubernetes controller model to interact with AWS APIs.</p>
<p><a href="https://dev.to/mda590/trying-out-aws-controllers-for-kubernetes-ack-1897" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Click here to read more!</a></p>]]></description></item><item><title>Inside the AWS re:Invent Session Bot</title><link>http://example.org/posts/2018-11-23-inside-reinvent-bot/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>http://example.org/posts/2018-11-23-inside-reinvent-bot/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today, I posted the code which runs the re:Invent Bot session tracking service. At a high level, this service scrapes the re:Invent session catalog at regular intervals, stores session information in a database, and then if sessions are new or changed, a Tweet is sent out with the session information.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The goal of this post is to provide an inside look at the re:Invent Bot and share some of the AWS architecture which powers it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Introducing Route 53 Resolver for Hybrid Cloud</title><link>http://example.org/posts/2018-11-19-aws-hybrid-dns-resolver/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>http://example.org/posts/2018-11-19-aws-hybrid-dns-resolver/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>Early last year, <a href="https://medium.com/statuscode/hybrid-dns-for-the-enterprise-in-aws-5ba5a049bcb1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">I published an article</a> outlining the different options available for creating an enterprise-tailored hybrid DNS solution on AWS. This solution required EC2 instances, configuring DNS software, and a good amount of &ldquo;undifferentiated heavy lifting.&rdquo;</p>
<p>As AWS has matured their enterprise offerings over the past several years, they&rsquo;ve identified hybrid DNS as a gap and I was so happy to hear they&rsquo;ve solved this problem by announcing the &lsquo;Route 53 Resolver for Hybrid Cloud&rsquo; service today!</p>]]></description></item><item><title>AWS Cloud9: First Look from an Ops Perspective</title><link>http://example.org/posts/2017-12-02-cloud9-infra-ops/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>http://example.org/posts/2017-12-02-cloud9-infra-ops/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>I just spent a couple of hours playing around with AWS’ new Cloud9 product, a fully browser based IDE with a lot of integration into AWS services.</p>
<p>I’m really impressed with the product overall. I have not ever had the chance to use Cloud9 prior to AWS purchasing it, but I can definitely understand the merits and interest by a lot of developers in a completely cloud-based IDE.</p>
<p>Here are some of my thoughts and findings that are more relevant from an infrastructure operations perspective. I know developers will be eager to get their hands on this product in the enterprise!</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Hybrid DNS for the Enterprise in AWS</title><link>http://example.org/posts/2017-04-16-aws-hybrid-dns/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>http://example.org/posts/2017-04-16-aws-hybrid-dns/</guid><description>&lt;p>AWS’ DNS offering, Route 53, is a great option for managing the basics of name resolution when resources exist solely within the AWS ecosystem. Route 53 integrates with most all of AWS’ services, offers great alias record functionality, and is easy to automate. However, for enterprises looking to make the move to AWS, especially in a hybrid deployment, Route 53 will most likely not be enough to provide all of the name resolution capabilities required. Because of this, hybrid DNS solutions need to be explored and implemented.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Simple Secrets Management via AWS EC2 Parameter Store</title><link>http://example.org/posts/2017-02-05-aws-ec2-secrets/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>http://example.org/posts/2017-02-05-aws-ec2-secrets/</guid><description>&lt;p>Amazon’s EC2 Systems Manager was launched at re:Invent 2016. It brings with it a lot of very useful tools meant to ease the administration and management of your EC2 instances and associated resources. One part of the EC2 Systems Manager suite is the Parameter Store. I think the Parameter Store is actually really quite powerful and can help secure your AWS environment in ways that may not be initially obvious.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2016 AWS re:Invent Recap</title><link>http://example.org/posts/2016-12-04-2016-aws-reinvent-recap/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>http://example.org/posts/2016-12-04-2016-aws-reinvent-recap/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>This past week I had the opportunity to attend AWS’ 2016 re:Invent conference for the first time. It was awesome! The connections I made and the things I learned will definitely stick with me for a long time to come! This year’s conference had over 30,000 people, and while that probably sounds overwhelming, it was overall run very well.</p>
<p><a href="https://medium.com/@mda590/aws-re-invent-2016-recap-338cc518f866#.bxx9tl8m2" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Click here to read more!</a></p>]]></description></item><item><title>AWS Routing 101</title><link>http://example.org/posts/2016-10-01-aws-routing-101/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>http://example.org/posts/2016-10-01-aws-routing-101/</guid><description><![CDATA[<h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2>
<p>AWS makes routing simple by abstracting the complex configuration required when configuring hardware routers, and only requiring users of the platform to manage simple routing tables with a few fields. AWS’ underlying infrastructure handles the rest. That being said, there are still several different options for routing which need to be considered and then configured, based on the size and complexity of your AWS environment.</p>
<p>This post will cover the following topics:</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Twenty-Five - 24 Things I Did At 24</title><link>http://example.org/posts/2015-05-19-twenty-five/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>http://example.org/posts/2015-05-19-twenty-five/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>Tomorrow is my 25th birthday! As a child, it&rsquo;s always hard to imagine living to be a quarter century old, but here we are. And, hey, now I can rent a car without paying extra for my age!</p>
<p>As I reflect on the last year of my life, I realize I&rsquo;ve done so many things! I am 100% certain I&rsquo;ve missed a lot of crucial items in this list, but I am hoping this gives a good summary.</p>]]></description></item></channel></rss>